# Nazmul Quader Zinnuree

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/zinnuree
Email: zinnuree@gmail.com
Phone: +8801717133886
Skype: nzinnuree

## **Overview**

I am a Software Engineer with 12 years of experience, mostly in the Smart-Phone Application Technologies, including an unprevented 7 years in iOS Application Development. I have also worked on Smartcard Personalization & Payment Technologies; Messaging, GIS and Navigation Technologies, Java Enterprise Applications and Java Mobile Applications.

So far, I have found myself in various forms of leading roles in several companies. I have mentored software development teams under different work environments and have worked with people from diverse cultural & professional background. I used to write technical blogs in my leisure time.

## **Key Experiences**

#### Programming Languages

Objective-C (professional), Java (language expert), Swift (moderate), C/C++ (prior programming experience) and basic knowledge on a few more.

#### Application Development Experience

iOS App Development, UI/UX & Storyboards Development, Native iOS SDKs, Custom SDK Development, Core Data ORM, Networking, Source Code Reviewing, Memory Profiling, Appstore distribution.

#### Other Development Experience

Java Servlets, REST APIs, Java Mobile, Microservices, Google App Engine. Basic knowledge on Relational Databases and Web Technologies.

#### Standards and Guidelines

CSPO® (Scrum Alliance), Human Interface Guideline (Apple), Mobile/Digital Finance Technologies, Card Personalization (Kona), Key Management, EMV Payment Specifications, XMPP, SIP, GIS and Navigation.

## **Employment Record**

#### November 2016 - Now

#### Senior Engineer Kona Software Lab Ltd.

I introduced latest iOS technologies and concepts to the team. I mentored iOS team and trained them up. I converted software requirements and UI/UX guides to individual development tasks, coordinated the development process, reviewed code, coordinated test cycles and managed production deployments.

I supervised an R&D team on Card Personalization and also contributed personally as development & support engineer. I prepared profiles for Visa and Mastercard personalization, improved system performance and stability. I configured and handled commercial rollout to an internationally renown personalization bureau.

I have a significant contribution to an MFS project as Business Analyst, Solution Designer to Project Owner. I have collected business requirements from the stakeholders. I have analyzed, negotiated and finalized them as software specifications. I have ensured customer expectations are translated to functional products.

#### **Used Technologies**

iOS SDK, Swift, Objective-C, Java, Git, Jira, EMV, Card Personalization, Card Testing, HSM, Key Management, Digital Wallet, DFS, MFS, E-Commerce, Utility Bill Payment, Ticketing Systems, Queue Management, Call Center Design.

#### **July 2015 – October 2016**

#### Senior Software Engineer Quest Systems Ltd.

I researched on several audio codec libraries and improved the quality and efficiency of voice communication. I also integrated video calling, instant messaging and file sharing features to the existing mobile based communication platform.

#### **Used Technologies**

iOS SDK, Objective-C, XMPP, SIP, Networking, Audio Codec, Google Analytics, MixPanel, AppsFlyer

#### May 2011 - June 2015

# CTO & Co-founder ALGONYX

In this self-envisioned start-up, I used to make plans and execute them to meet organizational goals. I also pioneered the in-house application development plans. I established and managed the development teams.

Beside these, I contributed as a developer to the iOS projects. I also worked on Google App Engine projects, Cocos2D game development and Android application projects.

## **Used Technologies**

iOS SDK, In-app-purchase, Game Center, Graph APIs, e-Commerce, REST APIs, Cocos2D, Android, SDK Integration, Google App Engine.

#### July 2007 - April 2011

#### Software Engineer Structured Data Systems Ltd.

I worked as a J2ME application developer. I also contributed to a few J2EE web application projects. I developed several SDKs including a Tiled Map and a UI Library for CLDC enabled mobile platforms that were later reused in several other projects. Later, I started to work on iOS and developed a 3D navigation system based on real-time GIS data.

#### **Used Technologies**

GIS, 3D Navigation, iOS SDK 4.2, J2ME, Lucene Search Engine, J2ME, OpenGL ES, GPS, Location Based Services

## **Academic Qualifications**

**2002 – 2007** 

B Sc (Hons) in CSE Shahjalal University of Science & Technology CGPA – 3.48 (4.00)

## Programming Contest Experience

Beside my curricular activities, I participated regularly into online and regional programming contests.

- Between 2002 and 2007 I solved more than 400 problems on the UVA Online Judge problemset (User ID 1033217).
- My team secured 8th position in the EWUPC 2006, which was a national level programming contest.

## **Trainings & Certifications**

In February 2019, I have completed **Certified Scrum Product Owner**® (ID – 000891401) training conducted by the Scrum Alliance. The interactive workshop enriched my understanding the agile philosophies under the Scrum principals and how they can be practiced in a software development project.

#### **Professional Interests**

- Programming and Software Development.
- Micro-services, Clean Code, Application Development, Design Patterns, Digital Finance.
- Writing software development & programming blogs, reading books on best practices, solving programming problems, and listening to music.

#### References

Will be provided upon request